[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So when we want to visualize hierarchical relationships,
所以当我们想可视化 层次关系
there's a particularly good method for doing that called a tree map.
树状图是展现这种 层次关系特别好的方法
So as we visualize graphs, and graphs represent relations between data items.
所以当我们可视化一些图表时 图表则表达着数据之间的关系
One relation that we'll want to visualize often is hierarchical relationships,
其中一种我们想要展示的关系 就是等级关系
things like parents and child relationships, ancestry and
就像父母和孩子之间的关系
descendant relationships.
祖先和后代之间的关系
And so in an undirected graph if you have a tree,
在无定向的图中 比如你有一棵树
any of these nodes could serve as the root.
树上的任何节点 都可能充当根的角色
But often in layouts we can identify a root node.
但我们能经常在 布局中确认根节点
And we can look at ancestry and descendants relationships
我们可看出根节点和子节点的关系
based on that root node based on the edge distance from a node to that root node.
基于该根节点与其子节点的距离
In a directed graph, we can set up
在定向的图中 我们可以
a more definitive parent child relationship using a directed edge.
通过有向路径 建立更明确的亲子关系
And we can have child nodes point towards parent nodes,
我们可以让子节点 指向母节点
or the other way around if we set it up that way.
或者反过来 如果我们建立母指向子的方式
We can specify a root node that has no parent,
我们可以确定一没有母节点的根节点
in this directed edge representation.
如这个有向边径图所呈现的
And we can create hierarchies where a node could have multiple parents, where
以及我们可以创建层次关系 其中一个子节点可含有多个母节点
we could make them an actual tree, in which case each node has a single parent.
或者创建真实的树图 在这种情况下 每个子节点只有一个母节点
And then we can also speak of a tree depth,
我们也可以展示树的深度
which is basically the number of parents a node has at the bottom level of the tree.
即为树的底层某一节点 所拥有的母节点的数量
Or the number of descendants, the maximum number of descendants a root node would
或为从根节点沿一路经到叶节点
have along one chain of these edges.
所拥有的最多子节点数量
And so we often need to visualize these trees.
因此我们通常需要可视化这些树
This is an example from genetics of fish, and
这是一个鱼遗传学的例子
the nodes in this case are laid out radially.
在这个例子中 节点是辐射状的布局
And then the tree structure is shown on the inside.
树的结构展示在内侧
Here's another example from the Tree of Life.
这是 "生命之树" 的另一个例子
And you can go to this website and zoom in on this image and
大家可以在这个网站 放大该图像
see a lot more detail than is shown here.
看到比起这里展示的更多的细节
But this is a layout that shows a hierarchical relationship as well.
这也是展示层次结构关系的一个布局
One of the methods for
其中一个方法
displaying hierarchical relationships that I've found quite useful is treemaps.
我认为能非常有效地展示层次关系 就是树形图
Treemaps were introduced by Ben Schneiderman in 1992.
树形图由本·施奈德曼 (Ben Schneiderman) 于1992年提出
And, they map hierarchical organizations of quantities into areas, so
他们将量化的层次结构 映射到空间区域 因此
it's a very visual method for displaying hierarchies based on subset operations.
对显示基于子集合操作的 层次结构是一种非常直观的方法
And so, we have an example of this in a utility called WinDirStat,
那么我们要提到的这个例子 是称为WinDirStat的应用程序
which displays a Windows file system.
它展示了Windows的文件系统
And it represents the entire file system by this rectangle.
通过这个矩形 展示了整个文件系统
And then that root directory is subdivided into smaller rectangles
根目录被细分为 比其小的矩形
representing sub-directories.
来代表子目录
And each smaller rectangle is subdivided into smaller rectangles which
每个小矩形再进一步 细分为更小的矩形
are sub-directories of that subdirectory.
代表该子目录的子目录
All the way down to individual rectangles,
如此类推到单独的矩形
where each of these individual rectangles represents a single file.
每个单独的矩形 代表一个文件
And so it gives you this nice broad overview of your file system, but
它不仅为你的文件系统 提供了漂亮的全面概述
it also shows you how the file system is divvied up into individual directories and
还展示了文件系统 是如何细分为单独的目录
sub-directories and files.
和子目录以及文件
And so it's a good indication of quantitative views, in this case,
因此这是量化视图一个很好的例子
of disk space.
即磁盘空间的量化
It's telling me how my files and
它告诉我的文件和
subdirectories are taking up different amounts of disk space.
子目录是如何占用了 磁盘空间的不同数量
And so it's mapping disk space to area.
也就是将磁盘空间 映射到空间区域
And I can get a pretty good quantitative measure of that
因此我就能对该磁盘空间 有个很好的定量化测量
disk space based on the area relationship of each of these sub-rectangles.
即基于各个子矩形的 区域面积关系
So how do we compute a tree map?
那么我们是怎样计算树状图呢?
Well, if you're given some hierarchy, some tree.
如果提供给你一些层次结构 一些树
And for a tree map, it has to be a tree.
对于树状图 必须是一棵树
It can't just be a regular hierarchy.
而不能只是普通的层次结构
Each node has to have a single parent.
每个节点必须只有一个母节点
You have some value, usually at the bottom level.
通常位于底层 是一些数值
For that previous example,
对于刚才提到的例子
this would be the disk space taken up by each individual file.
这将是每个单独文件 占用的磁盘空间
And so we first need to do a bottom up procedure that takes our tree nodes, and
所有我们首先需要对树节点 采取自下而上的步骤
for the parent nodes of our tree,
对于我们的树的母节点而言
adds up the child nodes in order to assign them a value.
其赋值为其下的 子节点数值的加和
So now each of the parent nodes is equal to the sum of its child nodes.
因此现在各个母节点等于 其子节点的总和
This parent is equal to 4.
这个母节点等于4
It's 1 plus 2 plus 1.
1加2再加1
This parent is equal to 11, because it's 4 plus 4 plus 3.
这个母节点等于11 因为它是4加4再加3
And finally 16, which is the sum of all of these adds up to 16.
终值是16 这是所有这些节点总和为16
And then we're going to use that parent-child relationship and
接下来我们将使用该 母子关系
the values that it represents in order to subdivide some rectangular region.
及其代表的数值 以细分一些矩形区域
In order to display how these small quantities at the bottom are organized,
为了显示底层这些 小的数值是如何组成一个系统
as portions of this full 16 value at the top, at the root node.
它们占顶部根节点总值16的比例
And so the first thing we do is we need to subdivide our rectangle into portions
首先我们要做的是 将矩形切分
representing the first set of descendants, 11 and 5.
来代表其第一代的子节点 即 11 和 5
And so we subdivide the rectangle into a portion that is eleven sixteenths and
即将矩形按比例分割为 十六分之十一和
five sixteenths.
十六分之五
And so, we subdivide it horizontally with a single vertical division
我们在横向上分割矩形 以一条竖直分割线
at eleven-sixteenths of the way from this edge to this edge.
从这一边到另一边 划分出十六分之十一
Into a portion that's eleven-sixteenths and five-sixteenths.
分割后的比例为 十六分之十一和十六分之五
Now we have two portions,
现在我们有了两部分
and these portions are actually taller than they are wide.
这些部分的高度 都比宽度要长
So we're going to subdivide them vertically instead of horizontally for
我们将在纵向上分割它们 而不是横向上分割
the next step.
在下一步
So now we've got this portion here on the left representing 11.
那么现在左边的这部分 代表11
We need to subdivide that into portions representing 4, 4, and 3.
我们需要将其分割为若干部分 分别代表4 4和3
So we subdivide them into a portion that's four-elevenths along the way,
所以我们将它们分割成若干部分 沿这条线分割出十一分之四
another four-elevenths along the way, and then finally another
再用一条线分割出另一个十一分之四 最后是另一个
three-elevenths along the way, representing each of these three nodes.
十一分之三 分别代表这三个节点
And now these are wider than they are tall, so
现在它们的宽度长于 其高度
we're going to subdivide them horizontally instead of vertically at the next step.
所以接下来在横向上分割它们 而不是纵向地分割
And so we do this again, and we subdivide this top node into one-fourth,
我们重复这一步骤 我们将顶部节点横向细分为四分之一
two-fourth, and one-fourth portions horizontally.
四分之二 和四分之一
We do this with all the rest of the nodes,
我们对剩下的节点执行相同的操作
and we get this tree map of all of the nodes we see here.
就得到所有节点的这张树状图
And so here I've got 1, 2, 1.
这里我有1 2 1
One-fourth, one-half, one-fourth of this rectangle representing four units.
这个矩形的四分之一 二分之一 和四分之一代表了四个单元
I've got 1, 1, and 2 of this rectangle representing 4 units,
这个矩形的1 1 和2 代表了4个单元
and then 2 and 1 of this rectangle representing 3 units.
这个矩形的2和1 代表了3个单元
All together, those represent 11 units.
全部加起来 代表了11个单元
And on this side, these 5 units, that were five-sixteenths
在这一边 这5个单元 即十六分之五
of the entire triangle are being represented by 3 and 2.
就是这里的整个三角形 用3和2代表
And I've got a slightly thicker line here differentiating between them.
我在这里用较粗的线条 来区分它们
And then this 3 unit is by individual units here,
这3个单元 由单独的单元组成
and this 2 unit is by individual units here.
这2个单元 也为单独的单元组成
And so, we're using area and a hierarchy of area into finer and
因此 我们用面积和 面积的层次结构分成更小的
finer rectangles in order to divvy up this large rectangle into its component pieces.
和更小的矩形 以将这个大的矩形细分为其组成部分
You'll notice that for example,
大家会注意到在这里 举例来说
this rectangle here is eleven forty-eighths wide
这个矩形的宽度为 四十八分之十一
because it's one-third of eleven-sixteenths.
因为它是十六分之十一的 三分之一
It's one-third of the eleven-sixteenths on this side of this thick black line.
即在租黑线条侧边的 十六分之十一的三分之一
So one-third times eleven-sixteenths is eleven forty-eighths.
所以三分之一乘以十六分之十一 为四十八分之十一
This bottom, the height of this is equal to three-elevenths.
在底部这里 这个高度等于十一分之三
It was three-elevenths of this whole unit.
这是整个单元的十一分之三
And so we have three-elevenths times eleven forty-eighths is equal to
我们用十一分之三乘以 四十八分之十一就等于
one-sixteenth, which is exactly the portion one-sixteenth.
十六分之一 正好是其所占比重十六分之一
Where is it?
这账户在哪里？
Right here, one-sixteenth of the entire area that we wanted to represent.
就在这儿 整个区域的十六分之一 也正是我们想要表示的
And so that gives you a good visual connection between the area
因此在视觉上很好地展现了
of this tree map layout as a portion of the whole.
这个树状图排布面积 和整体的关系
And the organization of this node representing one unit of
这个节点的组织结构 代表了一个根节点单元
this root node representing 16 units.
其则代表了16个子节点单元
Can also see some of the difficulty in doing ordinal connections between area.
也能看到有些困难之处在于 建立区域之间的有序联系
This is 2 units of area, and this is 2 units of area.
比如这里是区域的2个单元 这也是区域的2个单元
If I didn't have these numbers here, it may not be as easy to see that this
如果我没有这里的这些数字 可能不那么容易发现
rectangle is the same area as this more square region is.
这个矩形的面积 和这个比较方形的区域的面积相同
So area's not that good at representing ordinal amounts.
所以区域并不能很好地 表现有序的数量
But it is a pretty good tool for representing quantities in general.
但总体上来说 它是 表示数量的好用的工具
So the tree map is a good method for visualizing hierarchies because it relates
所以树状图对于可视化层次结构 是一种好用的方法 因为它
the region of that hierarchy to a region on the screen, associating it with area.
将该层次结构与 屏幕上的与面积有关的区域相联系
That is, we've seen area can be a decent but
也就是说 我们可以将区域面积看作还不错的
not great method for ordinal relationships.
但不是最好的方法 来展示有序的关系
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community